<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | Cody Drolc</title>
    <link>/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2019 Cody Drolc</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently a PhD candidate in political science at the 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://politicalscience.missouri.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;University of Missouri&lt;/a&gt;. 
In the Fall of 2020, I will join the Department of Political Science at the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://sc.edu/study/colleges_schools/artsandsciences/political_science/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;University of South Carolina&lt;/a&gt;
as an Assistant Professor of Public Administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I study issues at the intersection of public administration and management, administrative politics, 
and public policy. Most of research focuses on the broader network of government 
oversight with a specific emphasis the relationship between executive branch agencies, 
Congress, and experts in improving accountability and performance. My work 
has been published in  &lt;em&gt;Policy Studies Journal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officials at all levels of government rely on expert administrators and 
auditing organizations to provide performance information and identify problem 
areas in public agencies. Important work has considered how
elected officials hold government agencies accountable, but scholars largely 
ignore oversight mechanisms within agencies that monitor the implementation and 
formation of public policies and communicate information to elected officials and 
agency leaders. My dissertation research explores the implications of
government-wide oversight initiatives (e.g., Inspectors General and Government
Accountability Office) in enhancing administrative accountability, effective
oversight, and agency performance. Through three empirical chapters, I examine
(1) oversight performed by civil servants; (2) monitoring of agency activities
by Offices of the Inspector General; and (3) the influence of elected officials 
on non-partisan institutions tasked with overseeing government agencies.
My dissertation demonstrates that even non-partisan, expert oversight is 
subject to political manipulation and has implications for our understanding
of accountability, performance, and effective oversight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A copy of my CV is available 
&lt;a href=&#34;files/Drolc_CV.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
